# ADENUGA, OLOLADE OLUBUSOLA

11, Didun Street,Off Baale, Bonojo, Ijebu Ode,Ogun state, Nigeria ololabusola@gmail.com; +234 - 8077270257

#### **SUMMARY**

Ololade holds a Master of Science degree in Entrepreneurship education and a Bachelor of Science (Education Major) degree in Accounting. For about six years, she has had basic experience of practicing her skills by working with different schools and organizations. She is very effective and efficient in administration and record keeping. As a pastime, she also interprets edits and proof reads pieces of write-ups done in English and Yoruba languages in which she is very fluent (oral and written). She also has working proficiency in pidgin English.

### PERSONAL INFORMATION

MARITAL STATUS: Single SEX: Female NATIONALITY: Nigerian

### SKILLS AND EXPERTISE

- Account and Entrepreneurship teaching
- Accounting, Administrative and Auditing practice
- Data Interpretation, Presentation and Reporting (*MS Excel, MS Word, MS PowerPoint*)
- Editing and proof reading of write-ups done in English and Yoruba languages
- Fluency in oral and written English and Yoruba languages
- Working proficiency in Pidgin English

### **EDUCATION**

University of Ibadan, Ibadan, Nigeria M.Sc. Entrepreneurship Education	2016
M.Sc. Entrepreneurship Education	2010
Tai Solarin University of Education, Ijagun, Ogun state, Nigeria <b>B.Sc(Ed) Accounting</b>	2010
Our Lady of Apostles Secondary School, Ijebu Ode, Ogun state, Nigeria Senior Secondary Certificate	2004

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Position:** Administrative/Account Staff June, 2014 to May 2015

Organization: Victocom Farms Ltd, Rasanwa, Ijebu Ode, Ogun state, Nigeria

**Responsibilities:** 

- Records of daily production of eggs
- Records of raw materials (feeds)
- Records of sales (income) and expenses
- Prepared the staff monthly statement of salary
- In-charge of other administrative operations

Position: Assistant Accountant Sept 2012- July 2013

**Organization:** Olive Branches Schools, Osogbo, Osun State, Nigeria

**Responsibilities:** 

- Prepared debtors' list, drafted reminders and notice of payments for debtors
- Issued receipts to pupils and students who paid school fees
- Kept financial books of records
- In charge of sales of exercise books, uniforms, sport wears and cardigans to students and pupils
- Wrote reminder and notice of payment to the debtors
- Performed any bank transactions on behalf of the school

Position: Assistant Bursar July 2011- May 2012

**Organization:** Osogbo Grammar School [Senior], Osogbo, Osun State, Nigeria

Account Section (National Youth Service Corps [NYSC])

### **Responsibilities:**

- Assisted in the preparation of staff monthly payment vouchers
- Issued receipts to students who paid school fees
- Kept financial books of records
- Wrote reminder and notice of payment to the debtors
- Performed any duties delegated by the management

Position: Treasurer Dec. 2011- Mar. 2012

**Organization:** Nigeria Christian Corpers' Fellowship, Osun State, Nigeria

## **Responsibilities:**

- Assisted in preparing the monthly financial report
- Issued expenses vouchers to the executives in charge
- Recorded incomes and expenses of the fellowship
- Disbursed cash through voucher by the president or general secretary of the fellowship
- Performed any duties delegated by the President and/or the general secretary

Position: Jan 2011- June 2011

**Organization:** Olukayode Olupayimo & Co, Ijebu Ode, Ogun state, Nigeria

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Analyzed bank statement of auditing clients
- Vouched cash book and the bank statements
- Prepared and managed petty cashbook

Position: Account Teacher Jan. 2010-Mar. 2010

**Organization:** Ogbogbo Baptist Grammar School (Senior), Ogbogbo, Ogun state

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Taught the Accounting to S.S. 2 students with prepared notes of lessons
- Marked and recorded students' scripts using pre-prepared marking scheme
- Effective teaching of rudiments of account which the students had been yearning to know for a long time

## **REFEREES**

# Professor M.O. Akintayo

Adult Education, Faculty of Education, University of Ibadan, Ibadan 08033786565 depoakintayo@yahoo.com

# Pastor (Dr.) Ayo Ifegbesan

Lecturer, Olabisi Onabanjo University, Ago Iwoye, Ogun State 08058877462 ifegbesanayodeji@yahoo.com

# Ogunsanya B. Aderemi

Chief Executive Officer Victocom Farms Ltd, Rasanwa, Ijebu Ode, Ogun State 080522533454 ogunsanyaab@gmail.com